Guide to the Ira Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual materials, 1965-2000s; Series X; 34
  - 47 VHS, 1 mini video cassette, 1986-1999 (Box 189)
    - Ira Cohen poetry reading at Tagine, 2000-09-08; YCALMSS625_0111; 1; 01:53:58 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319366)
    - Dorviz, 2002-02; YCALMSS625_0112; 1; 00:57:06 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319374)
    - Ira Cohen, undated; YCALMSS625_0113; 1; 01:26:06 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319382)
    - Ira Cohen Amsterdam and Tribute to Brian and Part Thunne, 1999-09; YCALMSS625_0114; 1; 03:04:50 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319390)
      PAL; 2X edit Luc Sala
    - Ruigoora Tower of Babel Ira Cohen, 1999-09-26; YCALMSS625_0115; 1; 00:37:47 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319408)
      PAL
    - Shots from Brussels (Hand Mirror Paper Eyes…) Eurosystem, undated; YCALMSS625_0116; 1; 00:34:20; PAL, 30 minutes (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319416)
      Shots in Brussels
    - Tape 5 New Year's Eve, undated; YCALMSS625_0117; 1; 00:37:03 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319424)
    - Tape 4 Reading at Me[lin?], 1998-12-29; YCALMSS625_0118; 1; 01:59:01 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319432)
    - Ira with Claudia and Bruno Eurosystem (Batman), undated; YCALMSS625_0119; 1; 00:27:48 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319440)
    - Tape 2 Loving in Budapest, December 23rd; YCALMSS625_0120; 1; 02:03:18 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319457)
    - Ira Cohen Crossing the Border Glasgow, 1997-05; YCALMSS625_0121; 1; 01:14:48 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319465)
    - Ira Cohen Paris Video Treatments, undated; YCALMSS625_0122; 1; 00:29:31; No audio on tape. (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319473)
    - Majoon Traveler (dub), 1998-03-19; 1998-04-02; YCALMSS625_0123; 1; 02:04:07 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319481)
  - 40 VHS, 1980s-1990s (Box 190)
    - Kings-VHS (copy), 1998-09-19; YCALMSS625_0124; 1; 01:12:20 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319499)
      Kings with Straw Mats; Master VHS from M-100
    - Crowing Rooster Arts Presents: Mickey Mouse Goes to Haiti: Walt Disney and the Science of Exploitation, undated; YCALMSS625_0125; 1; 01:30:51 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319507)
    - Quakebasket at Lst Planet Tonic Angus MacLise Celebration, 2000-08-21; YCALMSS625_0126; 1; 01:22:56 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319515)
    - Kumbh Mela II Hardwar Ira Cohen Kumbh Mela-Hardwar produced by Ira Cohen. II, 1986; YCALMSS625_0127; 1; 02:04:06 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319523)
    - Marty Top Portapak, undated; YCALMSS625_0128; 1; 00:15:29; Early black and white tape. The last minute has sound, but there is no video on tape. (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319531)
    - Ira Cohen Bob Bassara, 1998-11; YCALMSS625_0129; 1; 01:32:20 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319549)
    - Ira shorts via Ordi, 1999; YCALMSS625_0130; 1; 00:38:55 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319556)
    - KumbH Mela Excerpts Ira Cohen- director (World Music Institute), undated; YCALMSS625_0131; 1; 00:22:15 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319564)
      Note included with video details producers on the film.
    - Janine Pommy-Vega with George Gilson Museum Channel Video by George Gilson, undated; YCALMSS625_0132; 1; 01:04:39 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319572)
    - Hettie at ICA, undated; YCALMSS625_0133; 1; 00:20:55; There is some sync buzz in the audio. It cannot be removed. (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319580)
    - The Door is a Mirror The Mirror is a Door (Ira Cohen/L.L. Levi), undated; YCALMSS625_0134; 1; 00:09:38 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319598)
    - Majoon Traveler (dub), 1998-01-15; 1998-01-22; YCALMSS625_0135; 1; 02:06:11 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319606)
    - Jerry Lee Lewis, undated; YCALMSS625_0136; 1; 01:17:58 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319614)
    - Majoon 1 hour, 1998-01-22; YCALMSS625_0137; 1; 00:52:28 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319622)
    - Kumbh Mela rough cut part one, undated; YCALMSS625_0138; 1; 02:03:36; Time coded in real time. (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319630)
    - Kumbh Mela Hardwar Part I, 1986; YCALMSS625_0139; 1; 02:03:50; The video quality is poor, but viewable. (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319648)
    - Ondi for Ira at 106th 8L, 1999-02; YCALMSS625_0140; 1; 02:03:58 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319655)
    - Juncke footage for Ira Cohen copyright Laki Vazakas, undated; YCALMSS625_0141; 1; 00:30:59 (Box 190, Item barcode 39002102319663)
      1. Three short poems (7 min.)
      2. Original trailer (10 min.)
      3. Writer Elsie John excerpt (3 min. 5 sec.)
      4. Canadian money story (4 mins. 58 sec.)
      5. "Two for One" at La MaMa (1 min. 32 sec.)
      6. "Idea of Death" - room 828 (1 min. 50 sec.)
  - 43 VHS, 1980s-1990s (Box 191)
  - 33 VHS, 1980s-1990s (Box 192)
  - 42 VHS, 1980-2000s (Box 193)
  - 41 VHS, 1980s-1990s (Box 194)
  - 29 VHS, 2 video cassettes, 1980s-1990s (Box 195)
  - 42 VHS, 1990s-2000s (Box 196)
  - 33 VHS, 3 BETAMAX, 1 video cassette, 1980s-2000s (Box 197)
  - 182 audiocassettes, 1970s-1990s (Box 198)
  - 195 audiocassettes, 1970s-1990s (Box 199)
  - 190 audiocassettes, 1970s-1990s (Box 200)
  - 61 audiocassettes, 19 mini cassettes, 19 mini video cassettes, 1970s-2000s (Box 201)
  - 118 CDs, 1980s-2010s (Box 202)
  - 8 33 1/3 RPM records, 1960s-1989 (Box 203 (Record album storage))
  - 23 reel-to-reel audio tapes, 1965-1973, 2000s (Box 204)
  - 42 reel-to-reel video tapes, 1970-1976 (Box 205)
  - 4 reel-to-reel video tapes, 1970-1976 (Box 206)
  - 26 reel-to-reel video tapes, 1980s (Box 207)
  - "Master of Boyana" film reel canister #1; extra leads canister., 1980 (Box 208 (Oversize))
  - "Master of Boyana" film reel canister #2, 1980 (Box 209 (Oversize))
  - "Master of Boyana" film reel canister #3, 1980 (Box 210 (Oversize))
  - "Master of Boyana" film reel canister #4, 1980 (Box 211 (Oversize))
  - "Master of Boyana" film reel canister #5, 1980 (Box 212 (Oversize))
  - "Master of Boyana" film reel canister #6, 1980 (Box 213 (Oversize))
- Electronic media, 1980s-2000s; Series XI; 7 (Box 98, Box 214, Box 215, Box 216, Box 217, Box 218, Box 219)
  Boxes 98, 214-219: Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.